Guide to the Cornelius W. de Kiewiet papers, 1949-1951.
de Kiewiet, Cornelius W. papers, 1949-1951
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornelius W. de Kiewiet papers, 1949-1951.
3-7-2559
C. W. (Cornelius William), De Kiewiet 1902-
10.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, office files, meeting minutes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material from de Kiewiet's term in office, 1949 to 1951. Includes items relating to presence of communist influence among the faculty.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornelis Willem de Kiewiet was born in Rotterdam, Holland, in 1902. After moving to South Africa, he received his B.A. in 1923 and M.A. with honors in 1924 from the University of Witwatersrand, and his Ph.D. in Modern History from the University of London in 1927. From 1927 to 1929 he studied at the University of Paris and the University of Berlin. From 1929 to 1942 he was a professor at the University of Iowa in Iowa City, where he became a U. S. citizen in 1939. de Kiewiet came to Cornell University in 1941 as a professor of Modern European History, was appointed Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences in 1945, was named Provost in 1948, and served as acting president from 1949 to 1951.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The papers of Acting President Cornelis W. de Kiewiet consist primarily of correspondence and office files for the years of his tenure, 1949 to 1951. Some material deriving from his provostship (1948-1949) is included, as well as a small amount of correspondence of Theodore P. Wright, who followed de Kiewiet as acting president for a short time in 1951. The majority of the correspondence pertains to the routine operation of the university between the presidencies of Edmund Ezra Day and Deane W. Malott. Subjects include the relations between the Office of the President and Acting President de Kiewiet and individual members of the Board of Trustees, the faculty, students, and with several committees, programs, academic departments, and colleges within the University, including the Cornell University Medical College. Topics also include the adoption and operation of a balanced university budget, the planning and construction of new buildings and facilities including Statler Hall and Mann Library, the growth of the Office of University Development, the Cornell University Library, the Social Science Research Center, ROTC, and discrimination in the Cornell University Medical College; also, relations between Cornell University and New York State and Federal governments and agencies, particularly the New York State Education Department and the State University of New York, and with several corporations and educational and philanthropic foundations. A small amount of material pertains to enrollment quotas, communism, and relations with other colleges and universities. There is some personal material pertaining to Acting President de Kiewiet's selection in 1951 as the fifth president of the University of Rochester.
Major correspondents include Lucile Allen, Howard E. Babcock, Neal Dow Becker, Martin P. Catherwood, Gilmore D. Clarke, Edmund Ezra Day, Arthur H. Dean, Mary H. Donlon, Victor Emanuel, Alvin C. Eurich, Edward W. Fox, Frank E. Gannett, Larry E. Gubb, Solomon C. Hollister, Asa S. Knowles, Carleton C. Murdock, William I. Myers, Myron C. Taylor, Maxwell M. Upson, Elizabeth Lee Vincent, J. Carlton Ward, Robin M. Williams, Robert R. Wilson, and Theodore P. Wright.
SUBJECTS
Names:
De Kiewiet, C. W.1902-; Allen, Lucile.; Babcock, Howard E.; Becker, Neal Dow.; Catherwood, Martin P.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-; Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.; Dean, Arthur Hobson, 1898-; Donlon, Mary H.; Emanuel, Victor.; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian), 1902-1987.; Fox, Edward W.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957.; Gubb, Larry E.; Hollister, Solomon Cady, b. 1891.; Knowles, Asa S. (Asa Smallidge), 1909-; Murdock, Carleton C.; Myers, William I. (William Irving), 1891-1976.; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Vincent, Elizabeth Lee, 1897-; Ward, J. Carlton.; Williams, Robin Murphy.; Wilson, Robert R., 1914-; Wright, Theodore Paul.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Presidents.; Cornell University--Finance.; Cornell University--Libraries.; Cornell University Medical College--Administration.; Cornell University. Office of the President.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University. University Faculty.; State University of New York.
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; College presidents.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The original order of the Cornelis W. de Kiewiet papers as they were organized and kept by the Office of the President has been maintained, consisting of the customary university hierarchy which begins with the Board of Trustees and continues through the administrative offices of the university, the colleges, divisions, schools, departments, and programs at Cornell, and concludes with the New York State Education Department and State University of New York. Following the university hierarchy file is an alphabetical listing (beginning with Box 8 folder 23), encompassing miscellaneous topics, organizations, and individuals both outside and within the university.
CONTAINER LIST
- Statutes and By-laws of the University and Laws Relating to the University., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Board of Trustees.
- Board of Trustees Miscellaneous., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Wright, Theodore P.
- Membership on Board of Trustees., 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Olin, Franklin W.
- Minutes of Board of Trustees., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Agendas, Board of Trustees Meetings., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Actions Taken by the Board of Trustees Under Authority of the Board., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Reorganization of Committees of the Board of Trustees., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Board of Trustees - Executive Committee., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board of Trustees - Executive Committee. Greater Cornell Fund., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board of Trustees - Agenda., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.
- Board of Trustees - Agenda., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board of Trustees - Executive Committee., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Board of Trustees - Agenda., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Board of Trustees - Planning and Development Committee.
- Board of Trustees - Executive Committee., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board of Trustees - Investment Committee., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Babcock, Howard E.
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Parke, John S.; Becker, Neal Dow.
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee. Parke, John S., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee., 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Library extension.
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Board of Trustees - Planning and Development Committee., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Board of Trustees - Law Committee., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Board of Trustees - Membership Committee., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Board of Trustees - Faculty-Trustee Committee on Fine Arts., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Board of Trustees - Finance Sub-committee., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 26-32)
- Cornell University Library Board., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  McCarthy, Stephen A.
- Board of Physical Education and Athletics., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Kane, Robert J.
- Board on Student Health and Hygiene., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- New York Hospital - Cornell Medical Center Joint Administrative Board and School of Nursing., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Sloan-Kettering Institute.
- College of Engineering Council., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Willard Straight Hall Board of Governors., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Coffin, Foster M.
- Cornell University Medical College Council., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- New York State College of Agriculture Council., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Myers, William I.
- New York State College of Home Economics. Vincent, Elizabeth Lee., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- New York State Veterinary College., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Hagan, William A.
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations Council., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Architectural and Engineering Advisory Council., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Architectural Advisory Council., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Attendance of Meetings of Board of Trustees and Executive Committee., 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Deane W. Malott., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Decker, Neal Dow; Wright, Theodore P.
- Malott Folder - Applicants for Positions in Public Relations., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- The President and the Presidency., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Murdock, Carleton C.; Day, Edmund Ezra; Decker, Neal Dow.
- The President., 1946-50 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Day, Edmund Ezra.
- Theodore P. Wright., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cornelis de Kiewiet., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  University of Rochester.
- Cornelis de Kiewiet - Curriculum Vitae., 1949-51 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Edmund Ezra Day., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Edmund Ezra Day - Funeral., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Deans' Conference., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Cornell Under Livingston Farrand. Palmer, Archie M.; Howes, Raymond F., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Cornell University Committees, Deans Meetings Agendas., 1947-51 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Minutes of Deans' Conference Group., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- General Report on Publicity, 1947, 1948, 1949., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Replies to Letters on Public Relations., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Student Political Activities., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Fogel, Robert D. Labor Youth League; Academic freedom; Communism.
- Inside Cornell., 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Gripes of Various Kinds with Replies., 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Emanuel, Victor; Durr, Clifford; Day, Edmund Ezra. Communism.
- Office of the President., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Housing for Faculty, Students, and staff., 1947-49 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Reports of the President., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Report of President for State Colleges., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Administrative Committee of six to Advise President on Budget and Other Matters., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Faculty Advisory System., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Mimeo Policies to Staff., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Statements by the President., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Sympathy Letters., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Cabinet Meeting Minutes., 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Personnel Records for Academic Staff., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Office of the Provost., 1948-51 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Inventory - Office of the Provost., 1947-51 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Budget - Office of the Provost., 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Accounts - Office of the Provost., 1948-49 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters from Trustees and Alumni., 1948-51 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Noyes, Nicholas H.; Johnson, Herbert F.; Donlon, Mary H.; Babcock, Howard E.; Goodwillie, Edward E.; Mitchell, Albert K.; Gannett, Frank E.; Collyer, John L.; Gubb, Larry E.; Tuller, J. D.; Schurman, Jacob Gould; Strahan, J. C. J.
- Trips for CWdK., 1948-49 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Robert H. McCambridge., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Student-Administration Group to Promote Change on Campus., 1949-51 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Goldman, Arnold.
- Budget., 1949-51 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- University Faculty Committee on Budget., 1947-50 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Budget - School of Nursing., 1950 (Box 2, Folder S)
- Budget - Naval Science., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Areas for Consideration to Achieve Balance in the Budget., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Budget Committees., 1949-51 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Final Budgets, Administrative Departments., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Vice President for Research., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Machine Records., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Budget - Naval ROTC., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- University Faculty., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Murdock, Carleton C.
- Office of the Treasurer., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Office of the University Counsel., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Office of Public Relations and Information., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Office of Admissions., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Office of Dean of Men and Dean of Women., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Vice President - University Development. Knowles, Asa S. Office of University Development., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Budget Figures Assigned to Departments and Colleges., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Budget Scholarships, Fellowships, Loans., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Charges that Might be Made Against State Colleges., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Budget - Balances and Recommendations., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Budget Printing Costs., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Federal Funds., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- General Appropriations, Questions and Breakdowns., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Workmen's Compensation., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Unused Accumulated Budget Income from Restricted Funds., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Budget - University Owned Lands., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Tuition - Fees for Children of Faculty., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Tuition and Fees - Graduate School Fellowships and Scholarships., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Mimeograph Machine Pool., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Budget - School of Nutrition., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Budget - Final College Budgets., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Budget - College of Engineering., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Budget - Cornell University Medical College., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Budget - General., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Budget - College of Arts and Sciences., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Budget - College of Arts and Sciences., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Budget - Academic and Unrestricted Funds., 1948-51 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Budget - Administration., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Budget - College of Engineering., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Budget - Other Colleges and Departments than Arts, Engineering, and Administration., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Budget - Cornell University Medical College., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Budget - Comments by Plenary Committee Consisting of Representatives of the Faculty, the Deans, and Administration., 1948-50 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Budgets - 1951-1952., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- College of Arts and Sciences., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Budgets - 1951-1952., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Committee on Economy., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
- Vice President - University Development. Knowles, Asa S. Greater Cornell Fund; Office of University Development., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Committee on Planning and Development., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Greater Cornell Committee., 1948-50 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  Office of University Development.
- Greater Cornell Fund., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Million Dollar Fund for the Humanities., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- 80th Anniversary Program., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Committee on Coordination of Public Relations Program., 1948-50 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- University commission on Student Housing., 1948-51 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- New York State Dormitory Authority., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Procedures in Accepting and Acknowledging Gifts., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Reports on Gifts., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- B. F. Goodrich Gift to Cornell., 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  Collyer, John L.
- Greater Cornell Fund., 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Wright, Theodore P.; Knowles, Asa S. Greater Cornell Committee; Office of University Development.
- Task Forces., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- School of Nutrition Task Force., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Task Force for Dormitories at Cornell., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Cornell University Council., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Wright, Theodore P.; Knowles, Asa S.
- Cornell University Medical College Dormitories., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Emerson, Willard I.; Hinsey, Joseph C.
- Parents' Program., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Vice President for Research., 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Wright, Theodore P.; Day, Edmund Ezra. Cornell Research Foundation.
- Research Projects., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- General Electric Trainee Program., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Institute of Statistics at Cornell (Proposed)., 1948-50 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Survey of Business and Administrative Policies., 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Patent Policy., 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Housing Research Center., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Beyer, Glenn H.; Loberg, Harry J.
- Brookhaven National Laboratory., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Malott, Deane W.; Wright, Theodore P.
- Vice President for Business., 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Burton, John E.; Rogalsky, George F.; Knowles, Asa S.
- Increased Efficiency of Physical Plant., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Dept. of Buildings and Grounds., 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Weather low, Hugh E.
- Space and Room Requests., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Dept. of Buildings and Grounds Haps and Plans., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Siting of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
- Anabel Taylor Hall., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Taylor, Myron C.; Day, Edmund Ezra; Mendenhall, W. W.; Knowles, Asa S.
- Anabel Taylor Hall - Windows., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Anabel Taylor Hall., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Taylor, Myron C.; Konvitz, Milton R.
- Chancellor's House., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Day, Edmund Ezra; Dean, Arthur H.
- Safety Division., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Fire Prevention Committee., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Barton Hall., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Civil defense.
- Teagle Hall., 1939-51 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Day, Edmund Ezra; Teagle, Walter C.
- Disaster Committee., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Statler Hall., 1944-51 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  School of Hotel Administration.
- College of Engineering - New Buildings., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Hollister, Solomon C.; Ward, J. Carlton; Upson, Maxwell M.
- Engineering Task Force., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Hollister, Solomon C.; Ward, J. Carlton.
- Moakley House., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Treman, Robert E.
- Board on Traffic Control., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- New York State Veterinary College., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Sage Chapel., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Day, Edmund Ezra; Meigs, Robert B. Sage Memorial Chapel burial rights.
- Residential Halls., 1947-51 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Freshmen in Dormitories., 1948-49 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Purchasing Office., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Employment and Placement Services., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  Unions.
- Budget - Stenographic Pool., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Salaries - Operating Staff., 1947-49 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Annual Salary Tabulation for Non-Academic Staff., 1947-48 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Job Classification and Evaluation., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Personnel and Employee Relations., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Disability Benefits., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Placement Service., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Alcoholic Beverages in University Buildings., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Travel and Transportation Study., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- South Hill Faculty Housing Project., 1948-50 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Strike., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Emanuel, Victor; Donlon, Mary H.; Noyes, Nicholas H.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Becker, Neal Dow. Student Committee for a Fair Election; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
- Electric Power., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Auxiliary Enterprises., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Office of the Treasurer., 1947-51 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  Wright, Theodore P.; Trousdale, J. B.
- Current Academic Budgets - 1949-1950., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Current Academic Budgets - 1948-1949., 1948-49 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Policy Concerning Use of Temporary Balances for Continuing Appointments., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Status of Budget., 1947-49 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- General Instructions on Budget., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Costs of Instruction in Arts and Sciences and the University., 1939-51 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Incomes from Government Research Contracts., 1948-49 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Study of Overhead Costs, State University., 1948-53 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Tuition and Fees., 1947-51 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Income for Endowed Colleges., 1947-50 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Veterans Administration Billing., 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Group Insurance., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Accumulated Income from Restricted Funds., 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Miscellaneous Studies and Figures Compiled by the Office of the Treasurer., 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Social Security., 1949-51 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Effect of the Wage-Price Freeze on Cornell University., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Secretary of the Corporation., 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  Meigs, Robert B.
- Secretary of the Corporation and University Counsel., 1949-50 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Estate of Addison P. Wilbur., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Estate of Cortlandt Hull., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Estate of Waldo F. Tobey., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Director of Admissions., 1948-51 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Williams, Herbert H.
- Quotas of New Students., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Williams, Herbert H.; Hollister, Solomon C.
- Quotas of New Students., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Mortality Study on Admissions., 1948-51 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Moore, Norman S.; Winsor, A. L.
- Policy Regarding Campus Transfer to the College of Arts and Sciences., 1948-51 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Admissions - Weekly Report., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Applicants for Admissions., 1950-51 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cornell Day., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Quotas for 1950-1951., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Quotas for 1949-1950., 1948-50 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Quotas for 1948-1949., 1947-48 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Registration and Enrollment Figures., 1948-50 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Fraternity and Sorority Averages., 1947-50 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Women at Cornell., 1948-50 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Alien, Lucile; McCambridge, Robert H. Committee to Study the Proposed Increase in the Enrollment of Undergraduate Women; Women students.
- Division of Unclassified Students. Murdock, Carleton C. Committee on Intercollege Transfers., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Secretary of the University., 1947-51 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Commencement., 1949-52 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Murdock, Carleton C. Committee on Commencement Arrangements.
- Committee on Conferences., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Office of Dean of Men and Dean of Women., 1948-51 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Counselor to Foreign Students., 1948-51 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Kerr, Donald C.
- African Students at Cornell., 1949-50 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Kerr, Donald C. Committee for African Students in America.
- Cooperation with Foreign Universities. Kerr, Donald C. Institute of International Education., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Counseling Services, Programs, etc., 1948-50 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Alien, Lucile.
- Fraternities., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Interfraternity Council; Restrictive clauses.
- Student Activities., 1949-50 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Policy Regarding Fraternities., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  van Patten, Morris D.; Donlon, Mary H. Interfraternity Council.
- Cornell Widow., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Daniels, Whitman; Adams, Bristow.
- Orientation Program., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Advisory Committee on Orientation., 1950-51 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Student Council., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- CREDO Cooperative House for Women., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Drinking Societies and Social Clubs., 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Donlon, Mary H. Majura Social Club; Beth L'Amed Social Club.
- Watermargin., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  Roosevelt, Eleanor.
- Round-Up Club., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Hindustan Students Association., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Women's Self-Government Association (WSGA)., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Alien, Lucile; Baldwin, Frank C.; Malott, Deane W.